

PROFILE

9 years of experience to obtain a position with a progressive web development company with a strong focus on creativity and problem solving. To find a position that is challenging, rewarding and provides an opportunity to expand my knowledge and abilities in creating client centric solutions.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Birth Date

29 Feb 1984

Nationality

Indian

Address

B-205, Raghubir Nagar, New Delhi – 110027

Marital Status

Married

CONTACTS

sahil242927@gmail.com

+91 9250483367

S sahil242927@gmail.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/mohd-sahil-

EDUCATION

M.Sc. (IT). 2016 - 2019 From Sikkim Manipal University

B.Sc. (IT) 2012 - 2016 From Sikkim Manipal University

SKILLS

JavaScript ES6, React JS, Redux, Redux-Saga, Nodejs, Express JS, MongoDB, Mongoose, firebase, GIT, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap 4, Rest web API services, JSON, jQuery, Webpack, Progressive Web Apps, MySQL, Golang, JIRA, Slack

MOHD SAHIL - REACT-NODE FRONTEND LEAD

PRIMARY REACT-NODE SKILLS:

- React Hooks
- Redux
- Redux Saga
- Context API
- NODE-EXPRESSJS API
- React Performance
- Styled Components
- Reselect
- Progressive Web

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND LEAD

DELOITTE

July 2019 - Oct 2019

Joined as a Team Lead on contract and working on a client site (Credit Suisse, Pune)

Responsibility: Managing team of 9 people along with coding, conducting DSM. Responsible for the delivery of the sprint on time.

Stack: ReactJS, Node JS, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, GIT, Bootstrap 4,

FRONTEND LEAD

XFRΙΔ

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Joined as a Team Lead on contract and working on a client site (McKinsey, Gurgaon)

Responsibility: Managing team of 6 people along with coding, conducting DSM. Responsible for the delivery of the sprint on time.

Stack: ReactJS, Node JS, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, GIT, Bootstrap 4,

TEAM LEAD

ARICENT

Mar 2017 – April 2018

Joined as a team lead and worked on well-known IBM product **"PowerHA".** It is a high availability system. Involved in the release of v7.3.

Responsibility: Managing team of 7 people along with coding, conducting DSM. Responsible for the delivery of the sprint on time.

Stack: ReactJS, Angular JS, Node JS, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, GIT Gerrit, Jenkins Bootstrap 4,

SR. PROGRAMMER

MOBILE PROGRAMMING LLC

Feb 2016 – Feb 2017

Joined as a **Sr. Programmer** on **contract** and working on a client site (**Juniper, Bangalore**)

Responsibility: Design and build APIs and UI for clusters systems, and also built CLI app using Golang for cluster system to get the details

Stack: Node JS, Express JS, Golang, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, GIT

SR. PROGRAMMER

CYBERLINKS PRIVATE LTD

Nov 2014 - July 2015

Joined as a Sr. Programmer on contract and working on a client site (TCS, Okhla)

Responsibility: Design and build APIs for an internal mobile app

Stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3

ACCOCIATE PROGRAMMER

CLAVAX TECHNOLOGIES

Worked on an online US based property portal (www.auction.com)

Responsibility: fixing bugs and build new feature on given visual designs

Stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3

TECHNIAL MEMBER STAFF

KONARK INFOCOMM PVT LTD

Aug 2012 – Jan 2012

Feb 2012 - July 2014

Worked on as a full stack developer and build this ISP portal (www.bharatnet.net)

Responsibility: fixing bugs and build new features

Stack: PHP, MySQL, Flash, JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3